I'm excited to be here to speak about vets,
أنا سعيد لوجودي هنا للتَحدث عن قدامى الجنود،
because I didn't join the Army
لم يكن انضمامي للجيش
because I wanted to go to war.
لأني أردت الذهاب للحرب.
I didn't join the Army because I had a lust
لم يكن انضمامي للجيش بسبب الرغبة
or a need to go overseas and fight.
أو الحاجة للسفر إلى الخارج والقِتال.
Frankly, I joined the Army because
بصراحة، أنا انضممت للجيش لأن
college is really damn expensive,
الكلية كانت مكلفة للغاية،
and they were going to help with that,
وكانوا سيساعدوني في ذلك،
it was what I knew,
لأن ذلك كان ما أعلمه،
and it was what I knew that I thought I could do well.
وكان ظني بأني سأقوم بعمل جيد.
I'm not a military brat.
أنا لست من مُحبي العسكرية.
No one in my family ever had joined the military at all,
لم يكن أي أحد من عائلتي قد انضم للجيش مطلقًا،
and how I first got introduced to the military
وتعرفي على الجيش لأول مرة
was when I was 13 years old
كان عندما كان عمري 13 سنة
and I got sent away to military school,
وقد أُرسلت بعيدًا إلى المدرسة العسكرية،
because my mother had been threatening me
لأن والدتي كانت تُهددني
with this idea of military school ever since I was eight years old.
بفكرة المدرسة السعكرية منذ أن كنت في الثامنة من عمري.
I had some issues when I was coming up,
كنت أثير بعض المشاكل في طفولتي،
"You know, if you don't get this together,
"أنت تعرف، إذا لم تقم بتحسين سلوكك،
I'm going to send you to military school."
فأنني سوف أقوم بإرسالك إلى المدرسة العسكرية"
And I'd look at her, and I'd say, "Mommy,
كنت أنظر إليها وأقول " أمي
I'll work harder."
سوف أبذل جهدي"
And then when I was nine years old,
وعندما أصبحت في التاسعة من عمري،
she started giving me brochures to show me she wasn't playing around,
بدأت إعطائي كُتيبات لتبين لي أنها لم تكن تعبث،
so I'd look at the brochures, and I'm like,
كنت أنظُر للكتيبات، وأقول،
"Okay, Mommy, I can see you're serious, and I'll work harder."
" حسنًا أمي , أستطيع أن ألاحظ جديتك، سوف أبذل جهدًا"
And then when I was 10 and 11,
وعندما أصبحت في 10 و 11،
my behavior just kept on getting worse.
صارت سلوكاتي أسوأ.
I was on academic and disciplinary probation
كنت تحت المراقبة الأكاديمية والانضباطية
when I was 11 years old.
عندما كنت في 11 من عمري.
And so when I was 13 years old,
وأيضًا عندما كنت في 13 من عمري،
my mother came up to me, and she was like,
جاءت إلي أمي وقالت،
"I'm not going to do this anymore.
"ليس بمقدوري فعل ذلك بعد الآن.
I'm going to send you to military school."
سوف أقوم بإرسالك للمدرسة العسكرية."
And I looked at her, and I said, "Mommy,
نظرتُ إليها وقلت "أمي،
I can see you're upset, and I'm going to work harder."
أرى أنكِ مستاءة سوف أعمل بجهد أكبر."
And she was like, "No, you're going next week."
فقالت، "لا، أنت ستذهب في الأسبوع المٌقبِل".
And that was how I first got introduced
وكان تلك أول مرة أتعرف فيها على
to this whole idea of the military,
فكرة الجيش برمتها،
because she thought this was a good idea.
لأنها اعتقدت أن تلك فكرة جيدة.
I had to disagree with her wholeheartedly
كان علي أن أخالفها الرأي بكل إخلاص
when I first showed up there,
عندما حضرت للمرة الأولى هناك،
because literally in the first four days,
لأنه حرفيًا في الأيام الأربعة الأولى،
I had already run away five times from this school.
كُنت قد هربت خمس مرات من هذه المدرسة.
They had these big black gates that surrounded the school,
كان لديهم بوابات سوداء تحيط بالمدرسة،
and every time they would turn their backs,
وفي كل مرة يديرون ظهوروهم للوراء،
I would just simply run out of the black gates
كنت ببساطة أجري للخارج عبر تلك البوابات السوداء
and take them up on their offer that if we don't want to be there,
وأنا بذلك أجرب جدية عرضهم في أنه إن لم ترغب في التواجد هناك،
we can leave at any time.
فيمكنك المغادرة في أي وقت.
So I just said, "Well, if that's the case,
لذا قلت "حسنًا، إذا كان الأمر كذلك،
then I'd like to leave." (Laughter)
فإنني أود المغادرة" (ضحك)
And it never worked.
وذلك لم يُفلح.
And I kept on getting lost.
وظللتُ أتخبط.
But then eventually,
ولكن في النهاية،
after staying there for a little while,
بعد مكوثي هنالك لفترة قليلة،
and after the end of that first year
وبعد نهاية تلك السنة الأولى
at this military school,
في المدرسة العسكرية،
I realized that I actually was growing up.
أدركت أنني في الحقيقة كنت أنضج.
and the thing that I enjoyed about the structure
والأشياء التي أستمتع بها حول تلك الهيكلة
was something that I'd never found before:
كانت شيء لم أجده من قبل:
the fact that I finally felt like I was part of something bigger,
في حقيقة الأمر شعرت بأنني جزء من شيء أكبر،
part of a team, and it actually mattered to people
جزء من فريق، وذلك كان يهم الناس بالفعل.
that I was there,
بأني كُنت هناك،
the fact that leadership wasn't just a punchline there,
حقيقة أن القيادة هناك ليست مجرد عبارة منمقة،
but that it was a real, actually core part
ولكن هذا كان حقيقيًا، في الواقع جزء أساسيًا
of the entire experience.
من التجربة بُرمتها.
And so when it was time for me to actually
وهكذا عندما حان الوقت بالنسبة لي فعليًا
finish up high school,
لإنهاء المدرسة الثانوية،
I started thinking about what I wanted to do,
بدأت بالتفكير فيما أود أن أفعله،
and just like probably most students,
وتماما مثل ربما معظم الطلاب،
had no idea what that meant or what I wanted to do.
ليست لدي فكرة ما يعني ذلك أو ما أريد أن أفعله.
And I thought about the people who I
وفكرت في الأشخاص الذين
respected and admired.
أحترمهم وأقدرهم.
I thought about a lot of the people,
فكرت في الكثير من الناس،
in particular a lot of the men, in my life
علي وجه التحديد الكثير من الرجال في حياتي
who I looked up to.
الذين أتطلع لهم.
They all happened to wear the uniform
وجميعهم يرتدون الزي الرسمي
of the United States of America,
للولايات المتحدة الأمريكية،
so for me, the question and the answer
لذا بالنسبة لي، السؤال والجواب
really became pretty easy.
في الحقيقة أصبح أسهل ما يكون.
The question of what I wanted to do
في سؤال ما أود القيام به
was filled in very quickly with saying,
شُغل بسرعة بقولي،
I guess I'll be an Army officer.
أعتقد أنني سأصبح ضابطا في الجيش.
and they trained me up,
وقاموا بتدريبي جيدًا،
and when I say I didn't join the Army
وعندما أقول أنني لم أنضم للجيش
because I wanted to go to war,
لأني أردت الذهاب للحرب،
the truth is, I joined in 1996.
الحقيقة هي، انضممت سنة 1966.
There really wasn't a whole lot going on.
لم تكن هناك الكثير من الأحداث الجارية.
I didn't ever feel like I was in danger.
لم أشعر بأني معرض للخطر.
When I went to my mom,
عندما ذهبت إلى والدتي،
I first joined the Army when I was 17 years old,
أولًا التحقت جيش عندما كان عمري 17 سنة،
so I literally needed parental permission
لذا حرفيًا أنا في حاجة لموافقة الأهل
to join the Army,
حتى أنضم للجيش،
so I kind of gave the paperwork to my mom,
لذا قمت بإعطاء طلب التقديم لوالدتي،
and she just assumed it was kind of like military school.
وافترضت أنها مثل المدارس العسكرية.
She was like, "Well, it was good for him before,
قالت، "حسنًا، كانت ذلك جيدًا له من قبل،
so I guess I'll just let him keep doing it,"
لذا أعتقد أنني سوف أسمح له بالاستمرار"،
having no idea that the paperwork that she was signing
وليس لديها فكرة أن الطلب الذي ستوقعه
was actually signing her son up
كان في الواقع تسجيل ابنها
to become an Army officer.
ليُصبح ضابطًا في الجيش.
And I went through the process,
ومررت عبر ذلك الإجراء،
and again the whole time still just thinking,
ومرة أخرى طوال الوقت مازلت أفكر،
this is great, maybe I'll serve on a weekend,
هذا شيء عظيم، وربما سوف أخدم في نهاية الأسبوع،
or two weeks during the year, do drill,
أو أسبوعين خلال العام، بدون جهد،
and then a couple years after I signed up,
وحينها بعد بضعة سنوات من توقيعي،
a couple years after my mother signed those papers,
بعد بضع سنوات منذ أن وقعت والدتي تلك الأوراق،
the whole world changed.
تغير العالم بأكمله.
And after 9/11, there was an entirely new context
وبعد 11/9، كان هناك سياق جديد كليًا
about the occupation that I chose.
حول الوظيفة التي اخترتها.
When I first joined, I never joined to fight,
عندما انضمامى في البداية لم أنضم للقتال،
but now that I was in,
لكن الآن أنا داخل ذلك،
this is exactly what was now going to happen.
هذا بالضبط ما سيحدث الآن.
And I thought about so much about the soldiers
وفكرت كثيرا جدًا بالجنود
who I eventually had to end up leading.
الذين في نهاية المطاف سأقوم بقيادتهم.
I remember when we first, right after 9/11,
أتذكر في البداية، مباشرة بعد 11/9،
three weeks after 9/11, I was on a plane heading overseas,
بعد ثلاثة أسابيع من 11/9، كنت على متن طائرة متجهة خارجًا،
but I wasn't heading overseas with the military,
ولكن لم أكن متوجها للخارج مع الجيش،
I was heading overseas because I got a scholarship
كنت ذاهبا في الخارج لأنني حصلت على منحة دراسية
to go overseas.
للذهاب خارجًا.
I received the scholarship to go overseas
تلقيت منحة دراسية للسفر إلى الخارج
and to go study and live overseas,
والذهاب للدراسة والعيش في الخارج،
and I was living in England and that was interesting,
كنت أعيش في انجلترا والتي كانت مثيرة للاهتمام،
but at the same time, the same people who
ولكن في نفس الوقت، نفس الأشخاص الذين
I was training with,
كنت أتدرب معهم،
the same soldiers that I went through all my training with,
نفس الجنود الذين قابلتهم خلال تماريني معهم،
and we prepared for war,
أثناء استعدادنا للحرب،
they were now actually heading over to it.
الآن بالفعل هم متجهون نحوها.
They were now about to find themselves
الآن هم على وشك أن يجدوا أنفسهم
in the middle of places the fact is
في وسط الأماكن في الواقع
the vast majority of people,
الغالبية العظمى من سكانها
the vast majority of us as we were training,
الغالبية العظمى منا كما في تدريباتنا،
couldn't even point out on a map.
ليس بمقدروهم حتى تحديدها في الخريطة.
I spent a couple years finishing graduate school,
قضيت بضع سنوات أُنهي دراستي العليا،
and the whole entire time while I'm sitting there
وطوال الوقت كله بينما أنا جالس هناك
in buildings at Oxford
في مباني جامعة أكسفورد
that were literally built hundreds of years
التي بُنيت حرفيًا مُنذ مئات السنين
before the United States was even founded,
قبل حتى تأسيس الولايات المتحدة،
and I'm sitting there talking to dons
وأنا جالس هناك أتحدث مع الأساتذة
about the assassination of Archduke Ferdinand,
حول اغتيال الأرشيدوق فرديناند،
where the entire time my heart and my head
في حين أن معظم الوقت كان عقلي وقلبي
were on my soldiers
مشغولًا بجنودي
who were now throwing on Kevlars
الذين الآن يضعون بذلات الكيفلار
and grabbing their flak vests
ويحملون ستراتهم الواقية
and figuring out how exactly do I change around
ويحاولون معرفة كيف بالضبط يمكنهم التبديل
or how exactly do I clean a machine gun
أو كيف بإمكانهم تنظيف السلاح
in the darkness.
في الظلام.
That was the new reality.
كان هذا هو الواقع الجديد.
By the time I finished that up and I rejoined
في الوقت الذي أنهيت فيه ذلك عُدت
my military unit and we were getting ready to deploy to Afghanistan,
لوحدتي العسكرية وكنا نستعد للانتشار في أفغانستان،
there were soldiers in my unit who were now
كان هناك جنود في وحدتي الذين كانوا الآن
on their second and third deployments
في عمليات نشرهم الثانية والثالثة
before I even had my first.
قبل حتى أن أحصل علي الأولى.
I remember walking out with my unit for the first time,
أتذكر خروجي مع وحدتي للمرة الأولى،
and when you join the Army
وعند الانضمام للجيش
and you go through a combat tour,
عند المرور بجولة قتالية،
everyone looks at your shoulder,
الجميع ينظر إلى كتفك،
because on your shoulder is your combat patch.
لأن على كتفك تعريقك الحربي.
And so immediately as you meet people,
لذا على الفور حينما تقابل أشخاصا،
you shake their hand,
وأنت تُصافحهم
and then your eyes go to their shoulder,
ثم تنتقل بعينيك إلى أكتافهم،
because you want to see where did they serve,
لأنك تريد أن ترى أين قاموا بالخدمة،
or what unit did they serve with?
أو ما هي الوحدة التي خدموا بها؟
And I was the only person walking around
وكنت الشخص الوحيد الذي يتجول
with a bare shoulder,
بكتف عارية،
But you get a chance to talk to your soldiers,
ولكن تحصل على الفرصة لمحادثة الجنود،
and you ask them why did they sign up.
وسؤالهم لماذا قاموا بالتسجيل.
I signed up because college was expensive.
أنا سجلت لأن الكلية كانت مكلفة.
A lot of my soldiers signed up for completely different reasons.
وهناك الكثير من الجنود سجلوا لأسباب مختلفة تماما.
They signed up because of a sense of obligation.
سجلوا بسبب الشعور بالالتزام.
They signed up because they were angry
سجلوا لأنهم كانوا غاضبين
and they wanted to do something about it.
وأرادوا فعل شيء حيال ذلك.
They signed up because
سجلوا بسبب
their family said this was important.
أن أسرتهم قالوا أن هذا مهم.
They signed up because they wanted some form of revenge.
سجلوا لأنهم أرادوا شكلا من أشكال الانتقام.
They signed for a whole collection of different reasons.
سجلوا لمجموعة كاملة من الأسباب المختلفة.
And now we all found ourselves overseas
والآن نحن جميعنا وجدنا أنفسنا في الخارج
And what was amazing to me was that I
وما كان مدهشًا بالنسبة لي هو أنني
very naively started hearing this statement
كنت ساذج جدًا لدي سماعي هذا البيان
that I never fully understood,
الذي لم أفهمه بشكل كافي،
because right after 9/11, you start hearing this idea
لأن مباشرة وبعد 11/9، تبدأ بسماع هذه الفكرة
where people come up to you and they say,
حيث يأتي الناس اليك ويقولون،
"Well, thank you for your service."
"حسنا، شكرًا على خدمتك"
And I just kind of followed in and started saying
وأنني كنوع من المسايرة أقول
the same things to all my soldiers.
نفس الأشياء للجنود.
This is even before I deployed.
هذا حتى قبل أن يتم إرسالي.
But I really had no idea what that even meant.
ولكن حقيقتًا لم تكن لدى فكرة عما يعنيه ذلك.
I just said it because it sounded right.
قلت ذلك لأنه بدا صائبًا.
I said it because it sounded like the right thing to say
قلت ذلك لأنه بدا لي من الصواب قول ذلك
to people who had served overseas.
للأشخاص الذين خدموا في الخارج.
"Thank you for your service."
"شكرًا على خدمتكم".
But I had no idea what the context was
ولكن لم تكن لدي أدني فكرة عن محتوى ذلك
or what that even,
أو حتى ما كان ذلك،
what it even meant to the people who heard it.
يعنيه للأشخاص الذين سمعوه.
When I first came back from Afghanistan,
عندما جئت لأول مرة عائدا من أفغانستان،
I thought that if you make it back from conflict,
كنت أعتقد بأنه لو نجوت من النزاع
then the dangers were all over.
ثم انتهت جميع الأخطار.
I thought that if you made it back from a conflict zone
كنت أعتقد بأنه لو نجوت من منطقة النزاع
that somehow you could kind of
وبطريقةً ما قمت
wipe the sweat off your brow and say,
بمسح العرق من جبينك وتقول،
"Whew, I'm glad I dodged that one,"
"يا للعجب، أنا سعيد لأنني هربت من ذلك"
without understanding that for so many people,
دون فهم أنه بالنسبة للكثير من الأشخاص،
as they come back home,
وبرجوعهم للوطن،
the war keeps going.
فالحرب ما تزال مستمرة.
It keeps playing out in all of our minds.
إنها تبقى تدور في عقولنا.
It plays out in all of our memories.
وتدور في ذاكرتنا.
It plays out in all of our emotions.
وتدور في عواطفنا.
Please forgive us
من فضلكم اغفروا لنا
when we spend one week in a place
عندما نقضي أسبوع واحد في مكان
that has 100 percent light discipline,
يحتوي علي انضباط تام بالأضواء،
because you're not allowed to walk around with white lights,
لأنه ليس مسموح لك بالتجوال بالمصباح،
because if anything has a white light,
لأن أي شيء يحتوي على ضوء،
it can be seen from miles away,
فإنه يمكن رؤيته من بعيد،
versus if you use little green
بالمقابل إذا كنت تستخدم أضواء خضراء خافتة
or little blue lights,
أو أضواء زرقاء خافتة،
they cannot be seen from far away.
فتلك لا يمكن رؤيتها من بعيد
So please forgive us if out of nowhere,
لذا من فضلكم اغفروا لنا إذا خرجنا من مكان،
we go from having 100 percent light discipline
يحث على انضباط تام بالضوء
to then a week later being back in the middle of Times Square,
بعدها بأسبوع كنا في منتصف تايمز سكوير،
and we have a difficult time adjusting to that.
ولدينا وقت قليل لنتأقلم مع ذلك.
Please forgive us
من فضلكم اغفروا لنا
when you transition back to a family
عند عودتك إلى أسرتك
who has completely been maneuvering without you,
التي تدير أمرها كليًا بدونك،
and now when you come back, it's not that easy
والآن لدى عودتك، ليس بتلك السهولة
to fall back into a sense of normality,
أن تنخرط في الشعور بالحياة الطبيعية،
because the whole normal has changed.
لأن كل شيء طبيعي قد تغير.
I remember when I came back, I wanted to talk to people.
أتذكر عندما عدت، كنت أرغب في التحدث إلى الناس.
I wanted people to ask me about my experiences.
أردت الناس أن يسألوني عن تجاربي.
I wanted people to come up to me and tell me,
أردت الناس أن يأتوا إلى ليقولوا،
"What did you do?"
"ماذا فعلت؟"
"What was it like? What was the food like?
"ماذا كان شعورك؟ كيف كان الطعام؟
What was the experience like? How are you doing?"
كيف كانت التجربة؟ كيف حالك؟"
And the only questions I got from people was,
والأسئلة التي طروحها علي كانت فقط،
"Did you shoot anybody?"
"هل أطلقت النار على أحد؟"
And those were the ones who were even curious
وأولئك هم الفضوليين بما يكفي
enough to say anything.
لقول أي شيء.
Because sometimes there's this fear
لأن في بعض الأحيان هناك رهبة
and there's this apprehension that if I say anything,
وهناك تخوف إذا قلت أي شيء،
I'm afraid I'll offend,
خشيتي أني سوف أسيء،
or I'm afraid I'll trigger something,
أو خشيت بأني سوف أشعل شيئا،
so the common default is just saying nothing.
وبالتالي فإن الفرضية بأني لن أقول شيئًا.
The problem with that
مشكلة ذلك
is then it feels like your service
هو أن ذلك يشعرك بأن خدماتك
was not even acknowledged,
ليست موضع تقدير،
like no one even cared.
كأنه لا أحد يهتم حتى.
"Thank you for your service,"
"شكرا على خدمتكم".
and we move on.
ونمضي قُدمًا.
What I wanted to better understand
ما أردت أن استوعبه بشكك أفضل
was what's behind that,
ما الغاية من وراء ذلك،
and why "thank you for your service" isn't enough.
ولماذا "شكرا على خدمتكم" لا تكفي.
The fact is, we have literally
في الواقع لدينا حرفيًا
2.6 million men and women
2.6 مليون من الرجال والنساء
who are veterans of Iraq or Afghanistan
الذين هم من قدامى الجنود في العراق أو أفغانستان
who are all amongst us.
وهم جميعًا بيننا.
Sometimes we know who they are,
في بعض الأحيان نعرفم من هم،
sometimes we don't,
في بعض الأحيان لا نعرف،
but there is that feeling, the shared experience,
ولكن هناك هذا الشعور، والخبرات المشتركة،
the shared bond
الرابط المشترك،
where we know that that experience
حيث أننا نعرف أن تلك التجربة
and that chapter of our life,
وهذا الفصل من حياتنا،
while it might be closed,
من الممكن إغلاقه،
it's still not over.
ولكن هذا لايعني أنه انتهى.
We think about "thank you for your service,"
نفكر في "شكرًا على خدمتكم،"
and people say, "So what does 'thank you for your service' mean to you?"
ويقول الناس، "ماذا تعني لك 'شكرًا على خدمتكم'؟"
Well, "Thank you for your service" means to me,
حسنا، "شكرًا على خدمتكم" بالنسبة لي تعني،
it means acknowledging our stories,
تعني الاعتراف بقصصنا،
asking us who we are,
بسؤالنا من نحن،
understanding the strength
فهم القوة
that so many people, so many people who we serve with, have,
بأن الكثير من الناس، والكثير من الأشخاص الذين خدمنا معمهم،
and why that service means so much.
ولماذا تلك الخدمة تعني لهم الكثير.
"Thank you for your service" means acknowledging the fact
"شكرًا على خدمتكم" يعني الاعتراف بحقيقة
that just because we've now come home
أنه لمجرد أننا قد وصلنا الآن للمنزل
and we've taken off the uniform
وقمنا بخلع الزي
does not mean our larger service to this country
لا يعني بأن خدماتنا الكبيرة لهذه البلد
is somehow over.
انتهت بطريقة أو بأخرى.
The fact is, there's still a tremendous amount
الحقيقة هي، لا يزال هناك قدر هائل
that can be offered and can be given.
يمكن تقديمه و بذله.
When I look at people
عندما ننظر إلى الناس
like our friend Taylor Urruela,
مثل صديقنا تايلور أورويلا،
who in Iraq loses his leg,
الذي فقد ساقه في العراق،
had two big dreams in his life.
كان لديه حلمان كبيران في حياته.
One was to be a soldier. The other was to be a baseball player.
كان واحد أن يكون جنديًا. والآخر أن يكون لاعب بيسبول.
He loses his leg in Iraq.
في العراق فقد ساقه.
He comes back
رجع
and instead of deciding that,
وبدلا من أن يقرر،
well, now since I've lost my leg, that second dream is over,
حسنا، الآن لقد فقدت ساقي، هذا الحلم الثاني انتهى،
he decides that he still has that dream of playing baseball,
قرر أنه لا يزال لديه حلم أن يلعب البيسبول،
and he starts this group called VETSports,
وقال أنه سيكون هذه المجموعة التي تسمى "فيت سبورتس"
which now works with veterans all over the country
والذي يعمل الآن مع قدامى الجنود من كل أنحاء الدولة
and uses sports as a way of healing.
ويستخدم الرياضة كوسيلة للشفاء.
People like Tammy Duckworth,
شخص مثل تامي داكويرث،
who was a helicopter pilot
والتي كانت طيارة مروحية
and with the helicopter that she was flying,
والمروحية التي كانت تحلق بها،
you need to use both your hands
كنت بحاجة إلى استخدام كلا يديك
and also your legs to steer,
وكذلك ساقيك للتوجيه،
and her helicopter gets hit,
وتعرضة مروحيتها للقصف،
and she's trying to steer the chopper,
وهي تحاول توجيه المروحية،
but the chopper's not reacting
ولكن المروحية لا تستجيب
to her instructions and to her commands.
لتعليماتها وأوامرها.
She's trying to land the chopper safely,
إنها تحاول الهبوط المروحية بأمان،
but the chopper doesn't land safely,
ولكن المروحية لا تهبط بأمان،
and the reason it's not landing safely
والسبب أنها لا تهبط بأمان
is because it's not responding to the commands that her legs are giving
لأنها لا تستجيب إلى التوجيهات من خلال ساقيها
because her legs were blown off.
لأن ساقيها قد تم نسفها.
She barely survives.
إنها بالكاد على قيد الحياة.
Medics come and they save her life,
أتى المسعفون وأنقذوا حياتها،
but then as she's doing her recuperation back at home,
ولكن بعد ذلك في أثناء استجمامها بالمنزل،
she realizes that, "My job's still not done."
أدركت بأنها، "لم تنجز وظيفتها بعد"
And now she uses her voice
والآن هي تستخدم صوتها
as a Congresswoman from Illinois
كعضو للكونغرس عن ولاية إلينوي
to fight and advocate for a collection of issues
للنضال والدفاع عن مجموعة من القضايا
to include veterans issues.
لتضم قضية قدامى الجنود.
We signed up because
وقعنا لأننا
we love this country we represent.
نحب هذا البلد الذي نمثله.
we believe in the idea and we believe in the people
نؤمن بالفكرة ونؤمن بالأشخاص
to our left and to our right.
الذين هم على يميننا أو يسارنا.
And the only thing we then ask is that
والشيء الوحيد الذي نطلبه هو أن
"thank you for your service"
"شكرا على خدمتكم"
needs to be more than just a quote break,
تحتاج لأن تكون أكثر من اقتباس،
that "thank you for your service" means
أن "أشكركم على خدمتكم" تعني
honestly digging in
التأثير بصدق في
to the people who have stepped up
الأشخاص الذين تقدموا
simply because they were asked to,
لأن ذلك ببساطة طُلب منهم،
and what that means for us not just now,
وما يعنيه لنا ذلك ليس فقط الأن،
not just during combat operations,
ليس فقط خلال العمليات القتالية
but long after the last vehicle has left
ولكن بعد فترة طويلة بمغادرة آخر عربة
and after the last shot has been taken.
وبعد أن تُطلق آخر طلقة.
These are the people who I served with,
هؤلاء هم الأشخاص الذين خدمت معمهم،
and these are the people who I honor.
وهؤلاء هم الأشخاص الذين أحترمهم.
So thank you for your service.
لذلك شكرًا على خدمتكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)